Guide to the Records of the Vice President of External Affairs, Naomi Levine RG.7.0
New York University Archives
Records of Office of the Vice President for External Affairs (Naomi Levine)
1964-1991
New York University Archives
Levine, Naomi B., 1923-
RG.7.0
15 Linear Feet in 30 manuscript boxes
Naomi Levine was Vice President of External Affairs at New York University (NYU) and led a $2 billion dollar fundraising campaign in her 22 years of service. This collection includes some of her correspondences and papers relating to the Office of External Affairs.
Access Restrictions
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject heading then chronologically within each subject heading. Boxes 20-30 consist of correspondence and supporting documents arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Naomi Levine is well known for her successful tenure as a fundraiser at New York University (NYU). She is also an accomplished lawyer, historian, author and owner/founder of a girls' camp in Upstate New York. A graduate of Hunter College and Columbia Law School, Levine held several positions at the American Jewish Congress (AJC). She was the Executive Director of AJC from 1971-1978, making her the first female in charge of a major Jewish organization.
Levine came to NYU in 1980. Her fundraising efforts helped NYU raise $2 billion in her 22 years of service, including individual gifts of $30 million from Leonard Stern, $25 million from the Tisch Family, $15 million from Helen and Martin Kimmel and an estate from Sir Harold Acton valued at approximately $500 million. Levine also started the Center for Philanthropy and Fundraising and the Bronfman Center for Jewish Life. She was a special advisor to NYU President John Sexton.
Custodial History
The records were transferred to the University Archives by the Office of External Affairs.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains records of the Vice President for External Affairs at New York University (NYU). Materials include correspondence, reports, speeches, publicity documents, background papers, development initiatives and budget information involving the Office of External Affairs. Some personal papers and correspondence belonging to Naomi Levine also are included.
Educational fund raising.; Universities and Colleges -- Administration; New York (N.Y.).; Programs (documents).; Budgets.; Correspondence.; Universities and Colleges -- Finance.; New York University. Office of University Development and Alumni Relations; New York University. Office of Public Affairs
- RESTRICTED - Alumni Federation, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- RESTRICTED - Annual Report, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- RESTRICTED - Bobst Dinner, 1 of 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- RESTRICTED - Bobst Dinner, 2 of 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Budget, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- RESTRICTED - Budget, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Budget, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Commencement, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Commencement, 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Commencement, 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- RESTRICTED - Commencement, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Commencement, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- RESTRICTED - Dental School, 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dental School, 1 of 2, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dental School, 2 of 2, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Development, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Development, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Development, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Development, 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Development, 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Report of NYU Task Force on the Financial Emergency, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- WSN Report of the Fiscal Review Group, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Report of findings: An Attitudinal Survey of the Constituencies Important to NYU's Undergraduate Recruitment Program, pt 1, 2, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Report of Findings: Undergraduate Recruitment Program Survey, Pts 3, 4, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Graduate Education Survey, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Actual Cost Allocation Report, A-E, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Estimate Cost Allocation Report, A-#, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Analysis of the Alumni Federation of NYU: A Report to the President, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Press, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Budgets, External Affairs, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Budget, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Actual Cost Allocation Report, Sections A-E, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Press, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Press, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Press, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Executive Summary of the FY 1986 Federal Budget and NYU (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Research and Development Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- US Department of Agriculture Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- US Department of Commerce Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- US Department of Defense Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- US Department of Education Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- US Department of Energy Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- EPA Budget, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- National, State, and Local Government Budget Documents; Budget worksheets; Office of Health Affairs Annual Report; Law School; Irvington House, 1979-1990 (Box 6)
- Development, 1982-1987 (Box 7)
- John Brademas, Alumni Federation, Alumni Relations, 1979-1989 (Box 8)
- Alumni Relations, Federation, and Council; Albany, 1981-1987 (Box 9)
- Alumni Council, Fundraising, NYU Medical Center, Bobst Library, David Kriser, 1977-1991 (Box 10)
- Japan, Lucy Moses Foundation, Law School, Palm Beach, Parents Breakfast, 1981-1987 (Box 11)
- Press; Speeches, Brademas; Fundraising, 1983-1988 (Box 12)
- Fundraising, Hughes Medical Institute, Schools of Business, Washington, 1984-1988 (Box 13)
- Graduate School of Public Administration, Schuer Foundation, Washington, 1981-1987 (Box 14)
- Development, Rudin Foundation, Office of Student Life Annual Report, Student Affairs, 1981-1990 (Box 15)
- South Africa, Tisch School of the Arts, Humanities Council, 1977-1988 (Box 16)
- Senate, Speeches, Washington DC, 1978-1984 (Box 17)
- Urban Research Center, 1978-1983 (Box 18)
- John Brademas speeches; articles and reports; Arnold Goren Material; Price Foundation, 1978-1984 (Box 19)
- "Ad" - "AM", 1966-1980 (Box 20)
- "Am" - "Bo", 1968-1978 (Box 21)
- "Bu" - "Co", 1971-1979 (Box 22)
- "Co" - "De", 1969-1980 (Box 23)
- "De" - "He", 1975-1981 (Box 24)
- "Hu" - "Ps", 1969-1978 (Box 25)
- "Pu" - "Sa", 1964-1979 (Box 26)
- "Sa" - "Sc", 1977-1979 (Box 27)
- "Se" - "Tr", 1967-1978 (Box 28)
- Sesquicentennial, 1980-1982 (Box 29, Box 30)